Himanshu Sharma

Backend Java Developer



- - https://github.com/himkrishna

Profile

self-disciplined. hardworking, passionate Backend Java Developer with proficiency in Java, SQL, Spring Boot, Data Structures and Algorithms. Problem-solving mindset and ability to perform well in team collaboration. Looking forward to utilizing my current skillset and experience of working on projects to create a mark in the software industry and achieve organizational goals.

Professional Experience

Management Trainee, HSIL Limited 06/2019 - 12/2019 | Gurugram, India Joined as Management trainee for Marketing and sales

Territory Manager, *Brilloca Limited formerly* Known as HSIL Limited 01/2020 - 03/2022 | Bareilly, India Work as a territory manager in the assigned territory to manage sales and marketing of the territory, and also manages a team of RSOs

Area Sales Manager, Hindware Limited formerly known as Brilloca Limited 04/2022 – 05/2022 | Bareilly, india Promoted as Area Sales Manager

Projects

India Today News Website - Clone 🛮

- India Today is a news website. it offers news on everything from business, finance, politics, science, and technology.
- Features Navigation, User Friendly
- Areas of Responsibility: Front page, Bottom index, Business page
- Tech Stack: HTML | JavaScript | CSS | Git
- Collaborative with five team members in 4 davs.

Covid 19 Vaccination, *Ayushkaam* □

- The objective is to handhold the citizens to register and schedule an appointment for vaccination.
- Features: Login as Admin & User, Registration
- Area of Responsibility: Vaccine Controller
- Tech Stack: Spring Boot, Spring JPA.Hibernate
- Collaborative with five team members in 4 davs.

Education

Full Stack Web Development, Masai School

04/2022 - present

Courses

- Web Development
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Soft Skills

Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech.) in Civil

Engineering, *GLA University*

08/2015 - 05/2019 | Mathura, India

Intermediate CBSE Board,

Happy Blue Bird Public School 04/2013 - 05/2014

SSC CBSE BOARD,

Happy Blue Bird Public School 04/2011 - 05/2012

Skills

Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, SpringBoot

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Leadership, Adaptability, Problemsolving